<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Self-Paced</title>
    <link>/010_introduction.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Self-Paced</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/010_introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Foreword</title>
      <link>/010_introduction/10_foreword.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/010_introduction/10_foreword.html</guid>
      <description>Kong Konnect Kong Konnect is a service connectivity platform that provides technology teams at multi-cloud and hybrid organizations the “architectural freedom” to build APIs and services anywhere. Kong’s service connectivity platform provides a ﬂexible, technology-agnostic platform that supports any cloud, platform, protocol and architecture. Kong Enterprise supports the full lifecycle of service management, enabling users to easily design, test, secure, deploy, monitor, monetize and version their APIs. Over 250 enterprises trust Kong Enterprise to reduce time to market by bringing applications and services to market faster, as well as increase infrastructure ROI by maximizing resource efficiency through improved automation and reduced overhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Challenge</title>
      <link>/010_introduction/12_problem_to_solve.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/010_introduction/12_problem_to_solve.html</guid>
      <description>The Problem Every organization is under pressure to innovate by providing compelling digital experiences. Organizations overcome this challenge through applications that are built with modern architectures using microservices and containers, managed through Kubernetes. These modern methods deliver the agility needs of the businesses.
Organizations break down legacy monolithic applications into smaller modern services, or they build new cloud native apps using microservices. The number of APIs is exploding, and connectivity between services becomes the critical backbone of your applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Kong?</title>
      <link>/010_introduction/14_partner.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/010_introduction/14_partner.html</guid>
      <description>Kong Konnect Enterprise The Service Connectivity Platform End-to-end service connectivity The platform integrates an API gateway, service mesh and ingress to provide end-to-end service connectivity across the full API lifecycle. It is the only platform that provides end-to-end connectivity between services within applications and across applications as well as exposes services at the edge.
Architectural freedom You can abstract network and security concerns from services so that developers can focus on building apps instead of pipes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Prerequisites</title>
      <link>/010_introduction/16_workshop_prerequisites.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/010_introduction/16_workshop_prerequisites.html</guid>
      <description>Workshop Prerequisites There are a few prerequisite tasks you must perform before getting started on this workshop. These are:
 access to an AWS account with proper permissions. eksctl kubectl
 httpie and curl jq fortio  In the next section, you will be instructed on how to configure all the prerequisite task stated above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/010_introduction/18_getting_started.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/010_introduction/18_getting_started.html</guid>
      <description>Getting Started Kong Gateway Enterprise is Kong’s API gateway with enterprise functionality. As part of Kong Konnect, the gateway brokers an organization’s information across all services by allowing customers to manage the full lifecycle of services and APIs. On top of that, it enables users to simplify the management of APIs and microservices across hybrid-cloud and multi-cloud deployments.
Kong Gateway is designed to run on decentralized architectures, leveraging workflow automation and modern GitOps practices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
